Nilesh Trivedi

CONTACT

Bangalore, India

hi@nileshtrivedi.com http://nileshtrivedi.com +91.773.7799.743

SUMMARY

I have worked in technology companies and startups across engineering, product management and sales roles for over 8 years. I co-founded a B2B product company with a Social CRM app. With an IIT and IIM background, I am an expert at full-stack development building scalable systems that delight the users. Some of my technical work can be seen here: http://www.nileshtrivedi.com/work.html

WORK EXPERIENCE

Two Roads Technologies, Bangalore

November 2014 — Present

Backend Engineer

- Built algorithmic trading systems and a web-based workbench for backtesting
- Tech used: Python, Ruby, Javascript, AWS, Docker, Redis and Discourse

Freelancing

July 2013 — November 2014

Independent Engineer

- Engineering projects for tech startups ranging from web and mobile apps to robotics to hardware, electronics, computer vision and machine learning
- Built an interactive physics simulation engine using Javascript and Canvas APIs. You can see my JSFoo presentation here: https://hasgeek.tv/jsfoo/2013-2/688-interactive-physics-simulation-in-the-browser-what-i-learned
- Tech used: Arduino, OpenCV, Python, Ruby, and Javascript

GupShup (earlier Webaroo), Bombay

June 2009 — July 2013

Lead Software Engineer

- Built and launched multiple web applications for Enterprise SMSGupShup serving thousands of users and delivering billions of messages per month
- Built tools for improving internal processes including analytics and customer support
- Development for GupShup's Android app
- Growth marketing with analytics and optimization of ad campaigns
- Tech used: Ruby, Rails, Java, JRuby, Android, Javascript

Lattice Purple Technologies, Noida

March 2008 — June 2009

Co-Founder

- Built and launched a social CRM app YouSuggest.us
- Successfully sold it to Indian media enterprises
- Built a dynamic and interactive trip-planning app using Javascript and Google Maps APIs
- Tech used: Ruby, Rails, and Javascript

Nilesh Trivedi 1

VoiceTech Solutions, Bangalore

May 2007 — June 2007

Business Analyst (Intern)

- Developed business plan for expansion into south-east Asia's IVR market
- Developed the channel partner program

HeadStrong, Bangalore

October 2005 — May 2006

Senior Associate

- Delivered multiple releases for Nuance Voice Platform
- Developed a number of speech-recognition applications using VoiceXML
- Tech used: Java, J2EE, VoiceXML

Tata Consultancy Services, Bangalore

July 2004 — October 2005

Assistant Software Engineer

- Development for American Express Global Website
- Tech used: Java, J2EE

QUALIFICATIONS

Sun Certified Java Programmer - 2005 Scored 100.0% in Coursera's Machine Learning class - 2013

EDUCATION

MBA (Marketing)

July 2006 — March 2008

IIM Lucknow

B.Tech. (AeroSpace Engineering)

July 1999 — May 2003

IIT Kharagpur

INTERESTS

Programming for fun, making music, reading and travelling. Over the years, I have presented at various conferences such as BarCamp, RubyConf, JSFoo, Makerfest etc. I blog at http://nileshtrivedi.com and my twitter and github accounts are @nileshtrivedi.

REFERENCES

Viswanath Ramachandran, Founder, Hippily (I was reporting to him when he was CTO at Webaroo) Email: viswanath.ramachandran@gmail.com

Tathagata Mitra, Product Manager, ZopNow (I worked with him when he was Director of Products at Webaroo) Email: tathagata@gmail.com

Nilesh Trivedi